<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title><![CDATA[ Plague Recipes]]></title>
  <link>https://frems.nomify.com</link>
  <atom:link href="https://frems.nomify.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
  <description><![CDATA[ The feed of updates to Plague Recipes ]]></description>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Lili’s Mince Pies ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/lilis-mince-pies</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_53107ea52d9d461b82904424d30a8890</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/lilis-mince-pies</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 08:40:08 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Lili’s Mince Pies ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Extremely delicious mince pie recipe from Lili. Makes 24.</p>
<h2 id="for-the-mince">For the mince</h2>
<ul>
<li>100g each currants, raisins, sultanas, chopped dates</li>
<li>50g each candied peel, glacé cherries (halved), flaked almonds</li>
<li>1 ripe banana, mashed</li>
<li>4 tbsp brandy</li>
<li>1 tsp each of nutmeg, ginger, mixed spice</li>
</ul>
<p>Mix. Don’t skip the banana, even if you hate banana. Trust me.</p>
<h2 id="for-the-pastry">For the pastry</h2>
<ul>
<li>250g butter, softened</li>
<li>150g caster sugar</li>
<li>1 egg yolk</li>
<li>400g plain flour</li>
<li>pinch of salt</li>
<li>icing sugar for dusting</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Preheat oven to <span class="small-caps">200C</span>. Brush two mini muffin trays with a thin layer of melted butter.</li>
<li>Cream the butter and sugar until pale. Add egg yolk and mix well.</li>
<li>Add flour and salt and mix until just combined.</li>
<li>Divide into two discs, wrap cling-wrap and stick in the fridge for an hour.</li>
<li>Keep a quarter of the pastry for the tops, and divide the rest into 24 balls. Use your fingers to squish each ball into the tray like it’s play dough to form the bottom case.</li>
<li>Fill each case with mince.</li>
<li>Roll out the remaining pastry dough and cut out your tops (I do a little star).</li>
<li>Bake for 12-15 minutes, or until golden brown on top.</li>
<li>Cool on a wire rack, then dust with icing sugar.</li>
</ol>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Creamy mushroom and miso pasta ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/creamy-mushroom-and-miso-pasta</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_825a6a91707d4bb5b3753b540d94b8a0</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/creamy-mushroom-and-miso-pasta</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:05:45 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Creamy mushroom and miso pasta ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dried pasta for 4 peeps</li>
<li>600g mushrooms, sliced (chestnut shrooms if you can get em, otheriwse swiss browns or buttons)</li>
<li>2 large handfuls of spinach</li>
<li>small bunch of chives (finely chopped + extra to serve)</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>sea salt</li>
<li>lots of black pepper</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="for-the-sauce">For the sauce</h3>
<ul>
<li>20gms dried porcini mushrooms</li>
<li>2 cloves of garlic</li>
<li>300gms silken tofu</li>
<li>2 tbsp brown rice miso paste</li>
<li>1/2 lemon, juiced</li>
<li>Salt</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Place the dried mushrooms in a bowl and cover with 150ml of boiling water. Leave to soak for 10 minutes.</p></li>
<li><p>Next, put the pasta on to cook.</p></li>
<li><p>While the pasta cooks, heat a frying pan to medium and add a drizzle of olive oil. Then add the mushrroms and a pinch of salt. Cook for 5-10 minutes, until tender.</p></li>
<li><p>When the dried mushrroms have done soaking for 10 minutes, put them in a blender with their soaking liquid and the rest of the sauce ingredients. Blend until smooth - season to taste.</p></li>
<li><p>When the pasta is ready, drain it, reserving some of the pasta water.</p></li>
<li><p>Stir the drained pasta, the sauce, the chopped spinach and the chives into the mushroom pan. Cook everything together for a minute or so, until the spinach has wilted, adding a little of the reserved pasta water if needed.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>Serve with sea salt and lots of black pepper (and spare chives).</p>
<p>From (Instagram)[<a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/CuP-bV2MGlQ/?igshid=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==" class="uri">https://www.instagram.com/reel/CuP-bV2MGlQ/?igshid=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==</a>]</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Chilli tamari cauliflower ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/chilli-tamari-cauliflower</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_7ad9ac3305c84299838fa6654ed255cb</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/chilli-tamari-cauliflower</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 17:36:00 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Chilli tamari cauliflower ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 head of cauliflower, cut into florets</li>
<li>1 tbsp oil</li>
<li>2 tbsp tamari</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="tamari-honey-sauce">Tamari honey sauce</h3>
<ul>
<li>2 tbsp cornstarch</li>
<li>1/2 cup water</li>
<li>1/4 cup tamari (or soy)</li>
<li>2 tbsp rice wine vinegar</li>
<li>1 tbsp honey</li>
<li>1 tbsp ginger, grated</li>
<li>1 tbsp sesame oil</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves, crushed and roughly chopped</li>
<li>Pinch of chilli flakes</li>
<li>2 tbsp oil</li>
<li>4 spring onions, chopped</li>
<li>1 red chilli, finely sliced</li>
<li>3 tbsp sesame seeds</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="to-serve">To Serve</h3>
<ul>
<li>Brown rice, cooked</li>
<li>Stir-fried seasonal greens (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>Preheat oven to <span class="small-caps">200C</span></p>
<p>On a baking tray, place the cauliflower florets and add the oil and tamari. Toss everything together and place in the oven to roast for 20 minutes.</p>
<p>While the cauliflower is roasting, make the tamari honey sauce. In a small bowl, add the cornstarch and water. Mix to combine and set aside.</p>
<p>In a small pot add the tamari, rice vinegar, honey, ginger, sesame oil, garlic and chilli flakes. Stir to combine. Then add the cornstarch water mix. Bring to the boil and stir constantly for 30 seconds. As you stir the sauce will thicken. Remove from the heat after 30 seconds and set aside.</p>
<p>In a pan, heat up the oil and add the spring onions, chilli and sesame seeds. Fry everything off for a couple of minutes, then add the roasted cauliflower and tamari and honey sauce. Stir everything together and continue to cook for another 3-5 minutes.</p>
<p>To serve, add everything into a bowl. Feel free to add stir-fried greens on the side.</p>
<p>From (Instagram)[<a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/CtYUmgURdGJ/?igshid=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==" class="uri">https://www.instagram.com/reel/CtYUmgURdGJ/?igshid=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==</a>]</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Ciannon’s Ginger Tiramisu ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/ciannons-ginger-tiramisu</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_8e8897ff8124447b9c36592aea6059a8</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/ciannons-ginger-tiramisu</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 11:15:31 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Ciannon’s Ginger Tiramisu ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>2 packs ginger nut biscuits</li>
<li>600mls whipped cream (or more)</li>
<li>Stones green ginger wine</li>
<li>Dark chocolate for grating to decorate</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>(Basically a chocolate ripple cake crossed with a tiramisu)</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Dunk ginger nut biscuits in ginger wine one at a time and glue together with a teaspoon-ish of whipped cream</li>
<li>Assemble in to log/cake shape in a pan depending on your preference</li>
<li>Cover with whipped cream and refrigerate for 6 hours or overnight</li>
<li>Grate chocolate over the top before serving (or decorate in some other fashion)</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>
<p>Log shape means you can cut it on the angle to get cute stripes, but you could just as easily layer it in baking dish like a regular tiramisu.</p>
<p>You could use half/half mascarpone and cream but it would significantly increase the richness.</p>
<p>Make sure you’ve got plenty of cream, running out before you’ve coated it all at the finish is a <span class="small-caps">PITA</span>.</p>
<p>Don’t get impatient and try and soak multiple biscuits at once - biscuit sludge lesson learned.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Nuts ‘n’ bolts ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/nuts-n-bolts</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_35b831e6e59140e38490a5d0ccc153b6</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/nuts-n-bolts</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 11:06:53 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Nuts ‘n’ bolts ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>A traditional Stringer family Christmas staple. Pretty sure this originally came from the back of a Nutrigrain packet in the 80s sometime. On paper it looks revolting, I get it, but it is genuinely, surprisingly delicious - a very pleasing mix of sweet and salty and crunchy and it takes <em>literally</em> minutes to make.</p>
<p>I frequently make at least a double batch and put it into glass jars for Christmas presents. Also excellent for general Christmas snacks. It rarely fails to please.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>350 gms Nutri Grain</li>
<li>375 gms Salted Mixed Nuts</li>
<li>1 packet Cream of Chicken soup mix</li>
<li>1 packet French Onion Soup Mix</li>
<li>2 tsp Curry Powder</li>
<li>1 tsp Mustard Powder</li>
<li>1/2 cup warm vegetable oil</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Add all dry ingredients into a large mixing bowl. Stir/mix well so all ingredients are mixed.</li>
<li>Add warm vegetable oil and mix through well.</li>
<li>Store in an airtight container.</li>
</ol>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Lucas Christmas Trifle ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/lucas-christmas-trifle</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_6ec231c50dc74950b09ec7e0780d390f</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/lucas-christmas-trifle</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 10:51:05 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Lucas Christmas Trifle ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>This is a family tradition - my sister and I would spend the whole year dreaming about our Christmas trifle, and how everyone loved it and it was the best thing ever. We never noticed that our cousins avoided it like the plague. Turns out that in 25 years of Christmases they had <span class="small-caps">NEVER</span> <span class="small-caps">ONCE</span> <span class="small-caps">EATEN</span> <span class="small-caps">IT</span>. They were turned off by the custard mixing in with the cream and the fruit. Wimps.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>2 tins of tinned berries - I like cherries and raspberries, but boysenberries and blueberries are good too.</li>
<li>600 mls of cream, whipped.</li>
<li>A Swiss roll, cut in to 2 centimeter rounds</li>
<li>A good slurp of sherry</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="christmas-custard">Christmas custard</h3>
<ul>
<li>2/3 cup of custard powder</li>
<li>3/4 cup of sugar</li>
<li>3 cups milk</li>
<li>3 eggs separated</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon vanilla</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>In a saucepan, blend the custard powder and sugar with a little cold milk. Add the rest of the milk and heat over a medium flame, stirring constantly until the mixture thickens (this is a very thick custard - it shouldn’t droop too much in to the other ingredients when it’s assembled). Turn the heat off and add the egg yolks, stirring quickly so it doesn’t turn in to scrambled eggs, add the vanilla at this stage too.</p>
<p>Allow to cool then fold in lightly beaten egg whites.</p>
<p>To assemble, drain one of the tins of fruit, and retain the juice from the other. Pop it all in the bottom of a large glass bowl and add a good slurp of sweet sherry. Line the jam roll rounds around the edges of the bowl on top of the fruit (don’t let it sink in too much - the jam should help it stick to the sides of the bowl to stay above the fruit line…). Top with the custard and then the whipped cream.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Lentil and chickpea soop ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/lentil-and-chickpea-soop</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_01a629977d1c479ea846fccc3d024a0f</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/lentil-and-chickpea-soop</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 14:15:17 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Lentil and chickpea soop ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Easy, tasty, healthy soup that takes 5 minutes to prepare and no more than 30 minutes from start to finish.</p>
<p>Serves 3-4 for a substantial main.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>180g puy lentils (or similar whole lentils)</li>
<li>240g (net) can of chickpeas</li>
<li>400g can of tomatoes</li>
<li>1 small handful each of coriander and flat leaf parsley, leaves finely chopped and stems tied into a bundle</li>
<li>1 red onion, chopped</li>
<li>1 tspn cinnamon</li>
<li>½ tspn ground ginger</li>
<li>1 — 2 tspn harissa or minced chillies</li>
<li>4 tblspn olive oil</li>
<li>juice of about ½ a lemon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>Heat the oil in a large saucepan then add the onion, frying until soft. Then, add the lentils, chickpeas, herb stems and spices, with 1 1/2 litres of water. Bring to the boil, then simmer for 15-20 minutes, or until the lentils are soft to your liking.</p>
<p>Take it off the heat and add the chopped herbs and lemon juice. Add salt and pepper to taste. Don’t serve the bundle of herbs.</p>
<p>Eat with crusty bread.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Ham Hock Lentil Soup ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/ham-hock-lentil-soup</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_a95311d0578848eba6968cc1636fcb53</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/ham-hock-lentil-soup</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 09:37:56 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Ham Hock Lentil Soup ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>This is one of Matt’s faves — long has he spoken of its powers, but I had never made it until yesterday.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 large ham hock</li>
<li>2 litres of chicken stock</li>
<li>1.5 litres of water</li>
<li>80ml extra virgin olive oil</li>
<li>1 leek, sliced</li>
<li>5 cloves garlic, sliced</li>
<li>2 sticks celery, sliced</li>
<li>1 carrot, peeled and sliced</li>
<li>1 bay leaf</li>
<li>4 sprigs of thyme</li>
<li>1 stick cinnamon</li>
<li>1/2 tbsp fennel seeds</li>
<li>1 tbsp cumin seeds, roughly grounded</li>
<li>1 red chili, sliced</li>
<li>1 tbsp tomato paste</li>
<li>1 can of crushed tomatoes</li>
<li>1/2 cup brown rice</li>
<li>1 cup red lentils</li>
<li>Mountain Bread</li>
<li>Plain yoghurt</li>
<li>Hot chili sauce</li>
<li>Fresh coriander</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>Cut hock into large pieces and place in a pot with the bone, 1l stock and water. Bring to the boil and then simmer, covered, over low heat for about 30 mins.</p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a saucepan and cook onion, leek, garlic, celery and carrot over medium heat for 10 minutes until golden, and then stir in herbs and spices.</p>
<p>Add cooked vegetables to hock meat with tomatoes, tomato paste and the rest of the stock. Simmer over low heat for 55 minutes until thick and tasty.</p>
<p>To serve, toast mountain bread in a sandwich press and break pieces over soup. Spoon over yoghurt, a little chili sauce, and a sprinkling of coriander.</p>
<h2 id="instant-pot-adaptation">Instant Pot adaptation</h2>
<p>Do the vegetables first (using the sauté setting), then transfer them to a bowl.</p>
<p>Cook the ham hock meat and bone in 2.5 litres of water on high pressure for 15 mins. (I totally forgot the stock! The soup is super-tasty without it though.)</p>
<p>Return the vegetables to the pot, along with rice, lentils, tomato paste and tomatoes. In my Instant Pot there was no room for more liquid, so I just cooked it all at high pressure for 30 minutes. It really was over-full, I probably should have removed the ham bone to reduce risk of death, but <span class="small-caps">HERE</span> I <span class="small-caps">AM</span>, telling you the tale of the very tasty soup.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Is Schmaltzy Chicken Cabbage the Greatest Bang-for-Effort-Buck Ever Created? ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/is-schmaltzy-chicken-cabbage-the-greatest-bang-for-effort-buck-ever-created</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_236047d567f14627b335de40abc6bb8e</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/is-schmaltzy-chicken-cabbage-the-greatest-bang-for-effort-buck-ever-created</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 11:02:53 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Is Schmaltzy Chicken Cabbage the Greatest Bang-for-Effort-Buck Ever Created? ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Everybody in our gang cooked Smitten Kitchen’s <a href="https://smittenkitchen.com/2020/04/roast-chicken-with-schmaltzy-cabbage/">roast chicken with schmaltzy cabbage</a> last year. It was the ultimate Pandemic Food: simple, rich, comforting, simple, chickeny, schmaltzy. On the weekend we returned to it after several months without (the pandemic goes on and on, after all), and it remains The Greatest. Never not be eating <span class="small-caps">SCC</span>.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Perfect poached eggs ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/perfect-poached-eggs</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_85290bcd0b4c47fd99e20c09cec14ad1</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/perfect-poached-eggs</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 08:36:52 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Perfect poached eggs ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>I always thought poached eggs were hard, but after digging about, here is a fool-proof way to get em perfick.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>Eggs (ideally room temp)</li>
<li>A little vinegar (optional)</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Note: the fresher the eggs, the better they’ll hold together</em></p>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>Put a fair amount of water into a saucepan - enough that the eggs will be fully submerged - and bring it to the boil. Choose a pan that’s big enough to accommodate the number of eggs you’re cooking without them rubbing up against each other.</p>
<p>Add a splash of vinegar - this helps keep the eggs together. Don’t use so much that your eggs taste vinegary though (unless you’re into that).</p>
<h3 id="strain-the-eggs">Strain the eggs</h3>
<p>This is a touch controversial, but eggs have two different types of whites: a runny one, and a thicker one that surrounds the yolk. Removing the runny one stops the white from blooming out when you put it in the saucepan and leaves you with a nice, neat ball of deliciousness.</p>
<p>Use a fine strainer and break the egg into it. Let the runny white strain through, then very carefully (so you don’t break it) pour out the yolk and surrounding firm white into a small bowl, ready for cooking. Use separate bowls if you’re cooking multiple eggs.</p>
<h3 id="cook-em">Cook em</h3>
<p>Once the water is boiling and your eggs are ready, remove the pan from the heat.</p>
<p>Carefully slide your eggs into the still water (it doesn’t need to be swirled) so they fall as neatly as possible.</p>
<p>Leave each egg in the water for 3 minutes (maybe a touch longer if your eggs have been in the fridge).</p>
<h3 id="fish-em-out">Fish em out</h3>
<p>At 3 minutes, use a slotted spoon to remove the egg. Drain as much as you can on the spoon, and then dab gently with a paper towel to remove any remaining watery excess.</p>
<p>Nom them.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Single pot barley with tomatoes ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/single-pot-barley-with-tomatoes</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_ad7402be35bd4b14b542352708da5ece</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/single-pot-barley-with-tomatoes</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 19:38:13 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Single pot barley with tomatoes ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>An excellent cold-weather staple in our house, originally from Smitten Kitchen (via Virginia). Super-easy, fast, hearty.</p>
<p>Serves 2 for a substantial main.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>2 cups water</li>
<li>1 cup pearl barley</li>
<li>½ a large onion, cut into very thin quarter moons (white is ideal, but whatevs)</li>
<li>2 cloves of garlic, thinly sliced</li>
<li>250 grams of lil tomatoes, halved/quartered (or big ones chopped up)</li>
<li>A bit of salt</li>
<li>Some dried chilli flakes (to your needs/desires)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon of olive oil</li>
<li>A few basil leaves</li>
<li>Grated parmesan (for serving)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="method">Method</h2>
<p>Put the water and barley into a medium saucepan while you prepare the other ingredients (this allows the barley to pre-soak a bit). Add the other ingredients (except for the basil and parmesan) as you get them ready.</p>
<p>Bung it all on the stove uncovered, set a timer for 30 minutes. Bring to the boil and then reduce to a simmer.</p>
<p>Stir from time to time.</p>
<p>Once your timer goes, test the barley for chewiness, leave it on a bit longer if you like it softer. When it’s done, add the basil strips and stir through.</p>
<p>Serve with some parmesan sprinkled over the top and some format of greenery (like broccolini or somesuch). Also very excellent with <a href="https://frems.nomify.com/perfect-poached-eggs">a poached egg</a> on top that can run down into the barley when broken open.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Nigella’s salmon kedgeree ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/nigella-s-salmon-kedgeree</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_e2e0413f8be7465a9b9f8c6fc3010b64</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/nigella-s-salmon-kedgeree</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 19:44:29 +1000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Nigella’s salmon kedgeree ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p><a href="https://www.nigella.com/recipes/salmon-kedgeree-with-lime-and-coriander">This is a winner</a> –&nbsp;it absolutely survives being made from freezer salmon fillets (as I discovered today, when a day-long power outage made some decisions for me), and it has few enough ingredients that it might almost be a pantry meal. I’m also guessing that it’s going to be a very good breakfast tomorrow.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ The Shallot Pasta ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/the-shallot-pasta</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_c78c7c45a6a1422389486951597f58af</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/the-shallot-pasta</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 19:35:58 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ The Shallot Pasta ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Alison Roman got mildly cancelled last year, but she has worked pretty hard to redeem herself and anyway I would probably make the famous <a href="https://cooking.nytimes.com/recipes/1020830-caramelized-shallot-pasta">Caramelized Shallot Pasta</a> even if Tony Abbott invented it. It’s so salty and rich. I was definitely &gt; 40 before I learned <em>how good</em> tomato paste is if you cook it down in a bit of oil.</p>
<p>If you are not an NYTimes subscriber, then you should definitely do that (<a href="https://frems.nomify.com/items/shallots.pdf">later</a>).</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Hot and sour soup ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/hot-and-sour-soup</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_01631213ccb54d2b8de24f8aa25176d7</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/hot-and-sour-soup</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 14:25:31 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Hot and sour soup ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>This is a simple, quick and very tasty chinese soup recipe that is excellent for treatment of your cold-riddled loved-ones, or just for general consumption. From Martha Stewart.</p>
<h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients</h2>
<ul>
<li>820ml reduced-salt chicken stock</li>
<li>2 tablespoons soy sauce</li>
<li>¼ to ½ teaspoon of finely chopped and crushed fresh red chilli</li>
<li>230gm shitake mushrooms, stemmed and caps thinly sliced</li>
<li>3 to 4 tablespoons of rice vinegar</li>
<li>2 tablespoons of cornstarch</li>
<li>1 large egg, lightly beaten</li>
<li>200gm tofu (soft or firm), cut into ¼ inch cubes and well drained</li>
<li>2 tablespoons of fresh ginger, finely grated</li>
<li>a couple of spring onions, finely sliced</li>
<li>a little sesame oil (optional extra for tastiness at the end)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="step-1">Step 1</h2>
<p>Combine the stock, soy sauce, chilli and 2 cups of water in a big (~5 litre) pot or saucepan. Bring to the boil using a medium heat.</p>
<p>Add the mushrooms, reduce the heat, and simmer for about 10 mins — until the shrooms are tender.</p>
<h2 id="step-2">Step 2</h2>
<p>In a small bowl, whisk together 3 tablespoons vinegar and cornstarch.</p>
<p>Bung it in the pot and then let it simmer, stirring, until soup is thickened. It should take about 1 minute.</p>
<h2 id="step-3">Step 3</h2>
<p>Pour the egg into the soup through a slotted spoon, and stir gently to form ribbons. Then gently stir in the tofu.</p>
<p>Remove it from the heat, cover it, and let it stand for 1 minute.</p>
<p>Put the ginger in a small sieve (or something that’ll help you squeeze out the ginger juice), and squeeze the juice into the soup (you can ditch the solids).</p>
<p>Taste, and (if required) add the remaining tablespoon of vinegar for a bit more of a kick, and/or a splash of sesame oil for some more flavour.</p>
<p>Sprinkle the spring onions over it to serve.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Bowl of Delicious Moose ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/bowl-of-delicious-moose</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_e2a9d0bbfd06447f9731ec898bb5ac2d</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/bowl-of-delicious-moose</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:55:43 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Bowl of Delicious Moose ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>I’ve discovered the world’s lowest-stress most flexible dessert: this <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/feb/06/yotam-ottolenghis-recipes-for-valentines-day-burnt-aubergine-feta-prawns-vanilla-butter-papaya-pickle-chocolate-coffee-tahini-mousse">coffee mousse with chocolate tahini sauce</a>. It feels infinitely variable depending on what you have on hand, all components of it can be made in advance, it’s quick and easy to assemble, and it’s extremely delicious. I made it last night, leaving out espresso powder (my can of it had hardened into coffee granite), and topping it with <a href="https://cooking.nytimes.com/recipes/1021203-sichuan-chile-crisp-sundae-with-peanut-streusel">Sichuan Peanut Streusel</a>, which I make regular batches of and store in the freezer — but you could just as easily top with salted peanuts or crumbled cookies or whatever you have. I wouldn’t bet against crumbled potato chips, but I’m weird.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Peanut Butter Noodles ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/peanut-butter-noodles</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_c716bfd6595144579f0e156e71eed9f7</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/peanut-butter-noodles</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 17:37:08 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Peanut Butter Noodles ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Rob wrote:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We left angel hair spaghetti for Aoife’s babysitter the other night. Inexplicably, she cooked the whole packet, ate a portion with Aoife and then put the rest of the pasta in a container in the fridge. Anyway, today I felt like a quick noodle lunch so I zapped a bowl of plain spaghetti in the microwave. Then I mixed together a drizzle of sesame oil, a tablespoon of crunchy peanut butter, a couple of glugs of soy sauce, a small teaspoon of chilli jam from Tia Con, and a splash of water to loosen it up. Toss through the spaghetti. Pretty good 2 minute noodles.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This reminded me of <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/jan/16/ofm-preview-recipe">this excellent sort-of recipe for Spicy Peanut Butter Noodles</a> by the wonderful Fuchsia Dunlop — you’ve almost certainly got all of the ingredients in the house already (if you don’t have Chinkiang vinegar, then run <strong>now</strong> to your nearest Asian grocery or Pieds), and it’s just enormously satisfying and delicious and nom. Hooray for noods with with <span class="small-caps">PB</span>.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Kimchi ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/kimchi</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_f3042417d34c4b9cb51220226e801a77</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/kimchi</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 08:29:39 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Kimchi ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>We always have kimchi in the fridge — I eat it by the forkful from the jar (ssh), and it’s central to two of our kitchen staple meals, <a href="https://www.chowhound.com/recipes/kimchi-soft-tofu-stew-soondubu-jjigae-29506">soondubu jjigae</a> (kimchi tofu stew) and <a href="https://cooking.nytimes.com/recipes/1021308-kimchi-bibim-guksu">kimchi bibim guksu</a> (kimchi noodles). I’ve generally used this <a href="https://www.masterclass.com/articles/how-to-make-kimchi-easy-recipe-and-tips">Alice Waters recipe</a> and it’s great, but it seems like actual Korean people include a potato or rice starch porridge as part of the ferment, and instead of or in addition to fish sauce (<span class="small-caps">TAME</span>) add salty squid or fermented shrimp. So next time I’m going to try <a href="https://www.maangchi.com/recipe/easy-kimchi">this more complete / authentic recipe</a>.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Tomato egg-drop soup ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/tomato-egg-drop-soup</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_58c75330fe6b4b5fbff3a65da07f7694</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/tomato-egg-drop-soup</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 07:37:59 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Tomato egg-drop soup ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Some version of Chinese tomato and egg-drop soup makes a very good quick lunch — <a href="https://www.instagram.com/stories/highlights/18083801056232389/">Lucas Sin Instagrammed</a> about this a few months ago, and where I’ve ended up is:</p>
<ul>
<li>In a smallish saucepan, fry 1-2 sliced spring onions and a little nub of sliced / julienned ginger in oil for a minute or so.</li>
<li>Add diced tomatoes or halved cherry tomatoes (about 1.5-2 medium tomatoes-worth?) and cook until soft, even a bit black.</li>
<li>Add a soup quantity of chicken stock like ~300ml — fresh, cubes, whatevs — and simmer for 5 mins.</li>
<li>Whisk one egg with a little bit of sesame oil and a little bit of water.</li>
<li>Remove the soup from the heat and spiral the egg gently into it, but <strong>don’t stir</strong>.</li>
<li>Bring the pot back to a simmer and loosen the egg a bit with a chopstick before pouring into a bowl.</li>
<li>Top with chopped green stuff like coriander and spring onions, plus Lao Gan Ma / other hot sauce.</li>
</ul>
<p>Really quick, easy, forgiving, flexible, delicious.</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item> 
    <title><![CDATA[ Saag Aloo Shepherd’s Pie ]]></title>
    <link>https://frems.nomify.com/saag-aloo-shepherd-s-pie</link>
    <!-- Use the following in future to prevent new RSS-post notifications when the permalink for a post changes: <guid isPermaLink="false">entry_ee19b0f8930f4b17921cbc8b929657bb</guid> -->
    <guid>https://frems.nomify.com/saag-aloo-shepherd-s-pie</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 06:31:45 +1100</pubDate>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[ Saag Aloo Shepherd’s Pie ]]></dc:creator>
    <description><![CDATA[  
<p>Last night I made something close to the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/feb/21/one-pot-vegetarian-recipes-anna-jones-pad-thai-shepherds-pie">saag aloo shepherd’s pie</a> from Anna Jones’s new book <a href="https://www.readings.com.au/products/24977237/one-pot-pan-planet">One</a>, which is out this week. I didn’t have spinach, so I used a combination of peas and sliced Brussels sprouts, although as I added the peas I realised that I had perhaps overdone the legumes. But it was excellent!</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.blot.im/blog_e0ccb09e96f44422adbfd1754970803a/_image_cache/0f0fe21e-0f47-48c3-9855-97c9b3de4b1d.jpeg" alt="Curry on toast" width="3000" height="3000"></p>
<p>Update: it was very excellent on toast the next day, too. Curry on toast! Where’s my James Beard award?</p>  ]]></description>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>